# CARTER JONES

# Student

#### **Carter Jones**

7070 Barley Drive Delta, BC V4E1T6

Phone: 604.250.7660

E-mail: 16carterjones@gmail.com

## **Skills**

- Team Work
- Communication Skills
- Written Communication Skills
- Critical Thinking
- Critical Problem-solving
- Listening/Learning skills
- Technologies
- Math Skills
- Machine Operation
- Technical Skills

The teamwork skills I bring to the workplace have grown through my experience in the VEX robotics community. I work with teams of other students in problem-solving environments learning to design and build competitive robots to compete on a world scale. Working in a team of 4 students has helped me with communication and troubleshooting and is one of the reasons I have accomplished so much in the robotics program. The team working environment has developed the skills that can be transferred to other workplaces allowing me to work with other people fluently and without issue. I can use critical thinking to problem-solve and learn new topics. I perform my very best in situations where I am learning new topics that I am not knowledgeable about. Helping others is what I enjoy; making others' day better allows me to make quick connections with anybody on any topic. Working in the engineering field allows me to be more adaptable in the workplace as being able to meet the needs of others is what I am best at. Having experience in a high-tech machining factory has helped me excel at being professional and responsible.

# **Experience**

My experience has been formulated through my time in engineering-focused school courses and working in a part-time house flipping job. I have gained experience in a professional workplace at Modern Engineering. Modern engineering provided me with a workplace to learn how to work with co-workers and how to complete task to a high standard. Working on household renovations I have used problem-solving skills which have me working on projects that are completed at a high standard. Lastly taking part in the robotics program at Seaquam Secondary has taught me outstanding communication and teamwork skills. Working with technologies has kept me learning and researching new technologies and how they are implemented in the

## **Kevin Grant / Proprietor/Owner**

June 2020 - PRESENT, Maple Ridge

This job taught me the skills required for renovation such as:

- Painting
- Finishing
- Tiling
- Grouting
- Landscaping
- Framing / Fence building
- Problem-solving
- Constructing small structures

## Modern Engineering / CNC Company

July 2022 - September 2022, Delta

A summer job that pushed my engineering knowledge and precision skills. Completing tasks to a high standard is the purpose of the position. I can apply high quality to any job.

## Safeway / Grocery Store

April 2023 - Present, Delta

Part-time job while I attend university.

## **Education**

everyday world.

### **Simon Fraser University**

SEPTEMBER 2023 - Present GPA - 3.2 (B)

## **Seaguam Secondary School**

SEPTEMBER 2018 - June 2023

Robotics 11 - Grade A (91%)

Engineering 11 - Grade A (93%)

Composition 11 - Grade B (81%)

Physics 11 - Grade A (87%)

Chemistry 11 - Grade A (86%)

French 11 - Grade B (81%)

Pre-calculus 11 Grade A (94%)

Law 12 - Grade A (91%)

Physics 12 - Grade A (90%)

English Studies 12 - Grade A (91%)

Calculus 12 - Grade B (79%)

Pre-calc 12 - Grade B (78%)

Chemistry 12 - Grade A (86%)

#### **Cougar Canyon Elementary**

SEPTEMBER 2010 - JUNE 2017, Delta, BC

#### **Awards and Achievements**

VEX WORLDS 2022 - Think Award - Presented to a team with most effective and consistent programming

VEX PROVINCIALS 2022 - Think Award

HIGH SCHOOL VRC TOURNAMENT - Amaze Award, Robot Skills 2nd Place

HIGH SCHOOL VRC TOURNAMENT - Robot Skills Champion, Design Award

HIGH SCHOOL SKILL TOURNAMENT - Robot Skills Champion

GORD TROUSDELL TEN TON ROBOTICS VRC TOURNAMENT-Tournament Champion, Skills Champion, Excellence Award PYRS BC VRC Mainland HS Championship- Tournament Champion, Skills Champion, Excellence Award

2023 VEX Robotics World Championship -

Create Award - Presented to team that demonstrates a creative approach to accomplish game objectives.

HONOUR ROLL - 2021 Grade 10 - 86% average in all courses

PRINCIPLES LIST - 2021 Grade 10 - 90% average in best 7 courses

HONOUR ROLL - 2022 Grade 11 - 86% average in all courses

PRINCIPLES LIST - 2022 Grade 11 - 90% average in best 7 courses

Graduate with honors

## References

Chris Lawrence - Modern Engineering - Manager, Operations

604-946-4110

Email: chris.l@moderneng.com

Kevin Grant - BC Hydro Civil & Structural Engineer/Owner HG Engineerning

778-231-8448

Email: kbngrant@gmail.com